<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on â„œğ”¬ğ”Ÿğ”Ÿğ”¶</title><link>https://h0rv.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on â„œğ”¬ğ”Ÿğ”Ÿğ”¶</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://h0rv.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Value Imperialism in the Future of Artificial Intelligence</title><link>https://h0rv.github.io/posts/value-imperialism-in-ai/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://h0rv.github.io/posts/value-imperialism-in-ai/</guid><description>I wanted to share my final essay for a Philosophy of Science class focused on Artificial Intelligence from the Spring of my 2rd year in University - April 25, 2022 to be exact. This was my first and only Philosophy class I ever took. With that said, I really enjoyed the in-person discussions (that I was deprived of due to Covid-19 pandemic) and some of the readings. It was by far the most academic papers I had to read in a course (several weekly readings), which often resulted in having a strong urge to take a nap after 20 minutes of reading due to the density of the texts.</description></item><item><title>Wireheads are Coming</title><link>https://h0rv.github.io/posts/wireheads-are-coming/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://h0rv.github.io/posts/wireheads-are-coming/</guid><description>The announcement of the Apple Vision Pro yesterday left me very conflicted. On one hand, the productivity gains that can be yielded by replacing the standard desk and monitor setups for myself and many others (and being able to easily travel with such large &amp;ldquo;screen space&amp;rdquo;) is very exciting. On the other, the dystopic future that was once predicted in 80&amp;rsquo;s science fiction is one step closer to becoming realized.</description></item><item><title>A Letter to Zuck</title><link>https://h0rv.github.io/posts/a-letter-to-zuck/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://h0rv.github.io/posts/a-letter-to-zuck/</guid><description>To Zuck,
Humans should not have access to virtually infinite streams of information. Likewise, humans also should not smoke cigarettes or alcohol, but they have an individual choice (as they should) to make an educated decision to do so or not. One difference, however, is that the latter products come with warning labels, while the former do not. This is of great concern to me, due to the impact it had on me and the imagined impact I can see it having on the younger generation currently, when all the things I talk about are only amplified to the extreme.</description></item></channel></rss>